

Chris Fletcher (Mr) Mobile:(+81) 070-2811-6113 Email: chrisfletcher1989@gmail.com

Japanese level: JLPT N2

Personal profile

I enjoy nothing more than a good challenge, and that's why I thoroughly embrace every problem that needs solving, and work hard to achieve the most efficient code. I am a dedicated developer with project experience in javascript, react, expressJS, SASS and postgreSQL. During my free-time I thrive off challenges and continuously work on improving my coding skills, such as through my projects outlined below. When we meet in person, one of the first things you notice apart from my grit determination, is my ability to work well with others and collaborate as a team.

Programming projects:

My projects and source code can be viewed live on my portfolio here:

https://chris-fletcher-portfolio.netlify.app/

- Celebrity recognition AI: Using the react framework for the front end, expressJS for the server and
 postgreSQL for the database, once logged in this web app takes an input as a link to an image, and
 returns a box around the face (if detected) as well as who the celebrity is likely to be. A challenge I
 overcame on this one was using state management on a larger scale than before. Breaking it down
 into manageable pieces while thinking of the overall picture really helped me to be able to
 accomplish this.
- Darts tournament bracket creator: Built with javascript, this web app allows users to seamlessly create a bracket for a darts tournament which randomises the players. It reacts to how many players are imputed into the system to create the correct sized bracket, calculate who plays who in a knock-out style system with the winner proceeding to the next round, and randomly assign the players in the first round. While this can be used for other sports too, the CSS is designed to look like a darts board. A challenge in this one was being able to take the inputs and randomise everything without a slow time complexity.
- Homepage for a nursery in Tokyo: Built using react for the index page, and vanilla javascript for
 the sub-pages, this is a template for a nursery which is set to open next year and is still working out
 their branding. The main page returns the local weather as an API, and sub pages include an events
 page which includes admin access to create/delete events which users can see. Listening carefully
 to the clients needs really helped me to be able to provide what she was after.
- Homepage for a real-estate photography company: The client didn't want any specific features, but with a heavy emphasis on CSS making an attractive website for users to see an image gallery, the company's marketing points, price-list etc.

Personal Achievements:

- Completing my first large programming project consisting of a front-end, back server and database in 2023.
- Passing the JLPT N2 in 2023.
- Completing the udemy course "The complete web-developer in 2023: Zero to mastery" in 2023
- Being promoted to senior manager at a Japanese start-up within 1 year if joining the company, in 2022
- Creating and running a successful photography business in 2015.
- Doubling the income of Haart's Earlsfield office immediately after employment.
- Winning the award for the SW London Sales Negotiator of the quarter award in 2012 (Barnard Marcus).



Chris Fletcher (Mr) Mobile:(+81) 070-2811-6113 Email: chrisfletcher1989@gmail.com Japanese level: JLPT N2

Skills

- Project experience in self taught javascript, react framework, expressJS server building and postgreSQL.
- Efficient at problem solving and trained through leetcode to narrow down the big O.
- Project experience on both the front and back end, as well as with databases.
- Knowledgeable of DSA patterns and their impact on performance.
- Experience using git commands and the git terminal.
- Experience using VS code, sublime text and replit.

Education

- Higher Education: The University of Hull, BSc Psychology; achieved in June 2010.
- Udemy course: "The complete web-developer in 2023: Zero to mastery" in July 2023.
- FreeCodeCamp course: Responsive Web Design in February 2023.
- Japanese Language Proficiency Test (JLPT): Level 2 in 2023

Recent experience

Mimmy inc (Minami Aoyama, Tokyo). June 2021-present Position: Guide Manager

<u>Duties Include:</u> The company teaches children about each country of the world in an aspiration to make global living easier for them in later-life. In charge of a team of roughly 20 domestic staff, and 50 workers overseas in various countries, the position was to oversee the service in general to assure it's quality and educational value to the children. Team-work and motivating those around me to succeed was an important element of this job, and I was able to learn a lot of such skills through it.

Nova (various locations in Tokyo). April 2017-June 2021

Position: English Language Teacher

<u>Duties Included:</u> Teaching of English materials as a 2nd language. I took a lot of pride in providing the best experience possible for the students and making their goals, my goals. I was working with English language students both in person and online, to all ages from kindergarten age all the way through to retirees.

AEON (Takadanobaba, Tokyo. August 2014-September 2015

Position: English Teacher

<u>Duties Included:</u> Teaching of a variety of English classes as a foreign language. The daily role included group and private adult lessons of all levels as well as all ages of children's classes. Aside from teaching the lessons, I was responsible of routine counselling of students to help them set and keep their goals. I also had targets for extra materials to sell to the students.